good day everyone it is our pleasure to
be part of this year's International
Conference in Innovation and educational
hosted by its prestigious open
University in Thailand and it is indeed
an honor for us to present in This
Global platform our research is
English language Proficiency curricula
in Southeast Asian countries
being proficient in the English language
brings a number of global advantages and
so English language proficiency has
become one of our most primary concerns
aligned with this an organization known
as Education First or EF yearly measures
the English language proficiency of
different countries the globally
published result is known as the EF
English proficiency index or efepi in
which almost all of the countries in
Southeast Asia annually participate
considering the annual results of efepi
we have observed that they are Southeast
Asian countries which are able to
maintain their high or very high
Proficiency in the language however it
is also notable that there are countries
in Southeast Asia which have been in the
low or very low proficiency bands over
the course of years
hence with the researchers decided to
conduct the study examining the English
language proficiency curriculum among
the Southeast Asian countries
specifically we sought to answer the
following questions
one tell me the English language
proficiency level of Southeast Asian
countries be described based on the EF
English proficiency index 2021 So What
observations can be seen in the English
education curriculum among the Southeast
Asian countries three what are the other
significant features of curricula in
Southeast Asian countries which
contribute in producing citizens with
high English proficiency level
in this study we mainly based our data
and conclusions and the results of EF
Epi 2021 Accord on the on the theory of
Bradley about Effectiveness model for
curriculum development indicators we
examine the curricular Implement that
implemented at this five years back
since the data of EF Epi 2021 were
likely the result of an English
curriculum implemented by a certain
country at least five years ago to
gather the data from this study the
researchers used the data mining
approach
for the results of the study you can now
see on your screen a table which shows
the result of aftpi of Southeast Asian
countries in 2021. Singapore possessed a
very high level of English proficiency
Philippines and Malaysia with high level
of proficiency Vietnam and Indonesia
with low proficiency while Myanmar
Cambodia and Thailand with very low
proficiency Brunei Laos and Timor Lester
were not included in the table because
they were not able to participate in
eseti 2024.
the next table shows the list of 11
Southeast Asian countries as well as the
starting level of instruction and number
of teaching hours implemented by their
respective English curricula
six countries started their English
instruction at grade one and they were
Singapore the Philippines Malaysia
Myanmar Thailand and Brunei four
countries started their English
instruction at grade seven and they were
Indonesia Cambodia Laos and timor-leste
meanwhile Vietnam was the only one
country which started its English
education at grade 3.
the table also shows that the number of
teaching hours among Southeast Asian
countries varied but it is notable that
relatively those countries which started
their English education at an earlier
level and taught the language within a
higher number of teaching hours are
those countries that also achieved
higher level of English proficiency
nevertheless it can be noticed that
despite teaching English at an earlier
level Thailand and Myanmar were still in
the lower proficiency band in this case
we have to consider other factors which
might have influenced the data such as
the country's Colonial history and
teachers expertise
foreign
was not colonized by English-speaking
countries unlike the Philippines and
Singapore in Myanmar Burmese is the main
language and with this studies revealed
that additional difficulties are
associated with the acquisition of the
English language
moreover Myanmar did not offer
specialized courses as part of their
press service teacher education this
means that student teachers could not
focus on attained expertise in a
particular subject such as English in
Thailand there were also a limited
number of English teachers so some
teachers were forced to teach Concepts
beyond their expertise for instance
reports shows that some English teachers
were 11 years old and Below were forced
to teach students age 15 to 17 but in
2016 kailan collaborated with the
British Council and launched a training
program which including improves the
expertise and strategies of English
speakers in Thailand by training
selected teachers who consequently will
train the other teachers
in terms of teaching approach Singapore
Thailand and Brunei implemented the
bilingual education system the Republic
of the Philippines adopted the K-12
curriculum together with the mother
tongue-based multilingual education
under the language and art
multi-literacies
meanwhile Malaysia Indonesia Cambodia
laws applied the communicative language
teaching approach moreover Indonesia
also applied learner-centered and
experience-based instruction lost used
the ordering one methods and demolition
suggests that the use of students native
language as medium of instruction
on the other hand Vietnam limited the
words that must be learned in each grade
its educational system focused on
accuracy rather than fluency lastly the
English curriculum of Myanmar was based
on the common European framework of
reference for languages to ensure that
the English language was taught in
context
considering the data guarded the
following significant features of
English were pointed out first the
bilingual education system
the data of 2010 Singapore census of
population show that the percentage of
residents who speak both English and
other language and Singapore has
increased by 13.5 percent compared to
the previous data gathered in 2000 and
2010. apparently language magazine
reported that it even increased to 48.3
percent in 2020.
second the language and arts
multiliteracy's curriculum in the
Philippines its Effectiveness is aligned
with the Timeless concept such as John
PJ's development learning theory since
the curriculum applies the spiral
progression way of learning the
children's cognitive skills in language
are being well developed
third City see how the activities in
Malaysia will also proven to bring
significant Improvement to students
English speaking skills including
grammar skills vocabulary skills
pragmatic competence and fluency
meanwhile some significant features from
the other Southeast Asian countries
include earlier English instruction
learner-centered and experience based
instruction
contextual teaching
and provision of continuous training for
English teachers
therefore in light of the findings of
the study the following conclusions were
drawn
in spite of differences South East Asian
countries have one thing in common they
continuously revise their English
curricula for further development
or Improvement the higher the number of
teaching hours is the higher the
possibility for students to achieve
higher proficiency
relatively countries in which English
instruction starts at an earlier level
also tend to yield students with higher
proficiency
however other significant factors such
as countries Colonial history and
teachers expertise May interfere
third the countries standing in efepi
2021 can serve as a basis to help
identify these significant features of
each curriculum which could be adopted
by other countries to Foster their
English education
the researchers have also constructed
the following recommendations
firstly
Southeast Asian countries May
participate really in on EF Epi for
continuous monitoring of improvement
next countries with lower proficiency
May recognize pictures of their existing
curricula that can be improved
finally countries with lower proficiency
may consider adopting the significant
features of English curricula in
Southeast Asian countries which
performed well
and that concludes our presentation we
believe that our research will hold a
huge contribution in fostering English
language education throughout the world
once again thank you very much